[ film reel ticking ]
[ wind whistling ]
[ whistling continues ]
[ door creaks ]
[ male number 1 screaming ]
[ instrumental music ]
[ whimpering ]
[ music continues ]
[ door slams ]
[ water gurgling ]
[ intense music ]
[ crow cawing ]
[ instrumental music ]
[ wind whistling ]
[ thudding ]
[ creaks ]
He 's gonna sell , move back to Illinois .
She had my gun .
I 'll get supplies while I 'm in town .
It would be good to get stocked up before winter sets in .
How did she get my gun ?
You gotta keep your wits about you .
Will you do that ?
Won 't be long .
Couple of days , maybe .
[ instrumental music ]
[ music continues ]
Lizzy !
Lizzy , wake up !
- Isaac ? - Lizzy !
Lizzy !
We gotta get the baby out !
[ music continues ]
[ breathing heavily ]
[ sniffles ]
[ wind whistling ]
[ intense music ]
[ creaking ]
[ wolves growling ]
[ growling ]
[ panting ]
Aah !
[ growling continues ]
[ panting ]
[ growling ]
[ gunshot ]
[ breathing heavily ]
[ wolves growling ]
[ panting ]
[ intense music ]
[ grunts ]
[ sheep bleating ]
[ clucking ]
[ birds chirping ]
We got new neighbors .
They bought the old Bergson Cabin .
A man and his wife .
Did you invite them over for dinner ?
Of course . Said you wouldn 't take no for an answer .
What are they like ?
A little funny .
- Funny ? - Nervous ?
Huh .
Better get dinner started .
[ crickets chirping ]
This is the best food we 've had in weeks .
Lizzy , you 'll have to give my Emma a few lessons
on making a decent meal .
I 'd be happy to .
Mm .
You two have a hell of a lot to do
before the winter sets in .
Everyone said that this was the best time
of year to get started .
Well , sure , but between getting that old cabin livable again
and planting your garden ..
We 'll do what we can to help , of course .
Maybe I can bring my plow around tomorrow .
We could at least get your crops in the ground .
That would be a , a mighty big help .
- You 're German ? - Yes .
I was brought over as a child .
Thank you .
- How were your travels ? - Long .
- Meet anyone ? - Uh , a few people .
A family going to Oklahoma
some men , a reverend .
Is there a church nearby ?
Not enough people around here yet .
- Now many ? - Now ..
Four .
[ creaking ]
[ flies buzzing ]
[ buzzing ]
[ thunder rumbling ]
[ both laughing ]
[ door opens ]
[ laughing ]
Oh , my .
Is the rain always like this ? This intense ?
It can be .
Oh , my .
Lizzy , these are beautiful pieces .
Did you bring them with you from Saint Louis ?
No . Isaac made most of our furniture .
That 's incredible .
Isaac , you are truly talented .
My father made most of our pieces as well .
He was quite the man .
How long have you been married ?
Eight years .
Oh , my .
And no little ones ?
- We had a son . - Wasn 't the Lord 's will .
It 's none of my business , of course .
Ah , sometimes I don 't know when to stop talking .
And the rain ..
Well , I tend to get a bit restless .
[ moaning ]
Is that what we look like to them ,
just a little flickering light in the middle of nowhere ?
Perhaps .
What do you think of them ?
It 's nice to have people close .
Something I 've always longed for .
But ?
But it feels odd .
In cities , strangers stay strangers .
Here we don 't have that luxury , do we ?
Come to bed . It 's too cold to have the door open .
[ tapping ]
[ thunder rumbling ]
[ rain pattering ]
[ groaning ]
[ instrumental music ]
[ retching ]
[ panting ]
[ groaning ]
[ music continues ]
[ indistinct chatter ]
Are you sure they 're expecting us ?
[ sighs ]
Come on .
We were very comfortable in Illinois , you see ?
Be sure to hold firmly
and get the root .
Gideon couldn 't stand working for my father
as if it were something to be ashamed of .
He 's not strong like Isaac .
Like you .
Hm .
I 'm going to get some water for the men .
Be sure to bring some for us as well .
[ grunts ]
Isaac ?
[ instrumental music ]
[ music continues ]
I fear I 'll never really get clean again .
Something wrong ?
Just getting used to everything , I think .
That takes time .
This land is funny , you know ?
It plays tricks on your mind .
[ music continues ]
[ birds chirping ]
[ wind whistling ]
[ intense music ]
[ gun cocks ]
[ banging on door ]
It 's Emma , she ..
She 's not well .
Better to wait outside .
No point in us all getting sick .
It is not that kind of sickness .
We 'll wait outside .
[ crickets chirping ]
[ door opens ]
Emma ?
[ indistinct chatter ]
Give us this day our daily bread .
Forgive us our trespasses .
It 's coming for me .
Emma .
No one 's here but us .
Gideon and Isaac are outside
but in here it 's just you and me .
No .
No . This place is wrong .
We 're not supposed to be here .
And now it wants my baby .
You 're with a child .
Come on .
Don 't touch me ! Don 't ..
[ intense music ]
Is she pregnant ?
Uh , did she say she was ?
She needs rest .
Lizzy , what are you doing ?
Shh . It 's okay .
- You 're exhausted . - I 'm not .
I can 't rest because it 's coming for me .
No , Lizzy .
Please don 't do that .
No .
Lizzy , don 't .. Lizzy . Lizzy ! Lizzy !
Ah !
Don 't do that . Don 't do that !
[ muffled screaming ]
Shh !
Pull your wife out from under the bed
and tie her to it .
You alright ?
Fine .
It was hard enough when it was just the two of us .
And now we 're expected to look after them as well ?
Gideon should take her home .
She 's gonna hurt herself or one of us with her nonsense .
Is she really pregnant ?
She thinks she is .
[ instrumental music ]
[ music continues ]
[ door creaking ]
" At length , the worn out anxiety
" she determined to call loudly for assistance
" from her casement , and was advancing to it
" when whether the terror of her mind gave her ideal sounds
" or that the real ones did come
she thought footsteps were ascending .. "
Perhaps we should finish another time .
When you 're feeling better .
It 's just a person in the book .
It 's not a spirit .
I see .
You can keep it .
Have you thought of names for the baby ?
Not yet .
They 're coming in for lunch .
I 've seen something .
- Just now ? - At night .
I hear it too , whispering .
I 've told Gideon but he doesn 't believe me
tells me it 's the wind .
- There are many natural - - - It 's not .
You remember how many graves you passed on the way here .
[ instrumental music ]
I told Gideon we should turn back .
I said everyone would be dead when we get there and there 's - -
Hush now .
[ intense music ]
Please don 't be unpleasant in front of the men .
[ sighs ]
[ music continues ]
[ Lizzy singing in German ]
[ knocking on door ]
[ singing continues ]
[ wind whistling ]
[ sighs ]
Lizzy ?
[ knocking on door ]
Isaac .
[ wind whistling ]
[ intense music ]
[ indistinct howling ]
[ gasps ]
[ grunts ]
[ indistinct growling ]
My help cometh from the Lord , which made heaven and Earth .
He will not suffer thy foot to be moved .
The Lord is my keeper
the Lord is thy shade upon thy right hand .
The sun shall not strike me by day , nor the moon by night .
He will not suffer thy foot to be moved .
Behold , He who keeps Israel shall neither slumber nor sleep .
The Lord is my keeper .
[ screams ]
... which made heaven and Earth .
He will not suffer thy foot to be moved .
He that keepeth thee will not slumber ..
[ growling ]
[ screaming ]
Lizzy ?
[ wind whistling ]
[ praying in German ]
Lizzy ?
[ intense music ]
[ praying continues ]
Lizzy ?
Hey , hey , Lizzy .
English ! English !
Lizzy !
You 're alright .
I shouldn 't have left you alone like this .
What 's this ?
It 's nothing .
Have you been reading it ?
I glanced at it .
You don 't need to be filling your head with stuff like this .
You need to rest .
What I saw was real .
This is yours now .
- I don 't - - - No .
Promise me you will keep it by you at all times .
It will protect you . It will protect our baby .
And the next time you think you see a demon ..
... shoot it .
[ mellow music ]
[ intense music ]
[ gun cocks ]
[ sighs ]
[ wind whistling ]
[ indistinct whispering ]
What ?
What do you want now ?
Where are you ?
[ intense music ]
Aah !
What must I do to be rid of you ?
[ clattering ]
[ rumbling ]
[ screaming ]
[ sobbing ]
No ! Stop !
[ intense music ]
Lizzy , where 's your gun ?
Mara , damner of souls .
Abbadon , the destroyer .
That 's enough , Emma .
Succorbenoth ..
... bringer of jealous thoughts .
Enough .
Do you want to play a game ?
No .
Why not ?
You are not well , Emma .
You should rest .
Think of your baby .
I am , Lizzy .
Elizabeth .
Little lady Macklin .
I want you to know what I 'm going to name the baby .
And what 's that ?
I want you to guess .
I do not want to play a game , Emma .
Three guesses for if it 's a girl .
Mary ?
- No . - Sarah ?
Mnm-mnm .
Do you want a hint ?
It 's one of two names in this room .
Emma .
Elizabeth .
Why ?
Because you have been such a strong person .
I would not have survived without you .
Three guesses for if it 's a boy .
Gideon .
No .
Samuel ?
Lizzy , I 'm not a monster .
One more guess .
No hints this time ?
I don 't think you need one .
- Isaac . - Yes .
Why ?
You know why .
Mesimer , prince of pestilence .
Succorbenoth , bringer of jealous thoughts .
Mara , damner of souls .
Babael ..
... keeper of graves .
[ instrumental music ]
[ dramatic music ]
[ intense music ]
[ crows cawing ]
For I have never , not in my entire life
seen anything like this land .
The wind never stops .
Gideon has barely been able to do his part
in making this place livable .
My only comfort is the time I get to spend with Isaac .
He puts in extra hours in the long days here
away from Lizzy .
I am pregnant . I know it .
I can feel it inside of me .
Our baby .
[ grunts ]
[ breathing heavily ]
Succorbenoth , bringer of jealous thoughts .
Babael , keeper of graves .
Abbadon , the destroyer .
Mesimer , prince of pestilence .
Mara , damner of souls ..
[ sniffs ]
[ screaming ]
[ moaning ]
Isaac ..
... I 'm scared .
You 're doing fine .
I wanna die .
[ screaming ]
[ panting ]
It 's a boy .
[ Lizzy breathing heavily ]
Why isn 't the baby crying ?
Isaac ?
- Isaac , why isn 't .. - You stay right there , Lizzy .
He should be crying .
[ groaning ]
[ speaking in foreign language ]
[ hammering ]
[ instrumental music ]
Samuel .
It 's a good name , Lizzy .
[ wind whistling ]
He 'll use it more than I will .
[ groans ]
[ sighs ]
[ intense music ]
[ metal creaking ]
[ music continues ]
[ blowing ]
[ dramatic music ]
[ breathing heavily ]
[ cocks gun ]
I.. I am so sorry .
Reverend .
I do beg pardon .
I haven 't had much in the way of real food for weeks .
You out here alone ?
I came across an empty cabin about a mile east of here .
Kin ?
No .
Well , I 've been traveling a while ..
... spreadin ' the word of God .
I don 't suspect God has much business out here .
No longer a God-fearing woman , hmm ?
[ door opens ]
Mrs. Macklin , thank you so much .
You have been more than hospitable .
You shouldn 't be out at night .
The Harper cabin is empty and you 'll be comfortable there .
You can head out in the morning .
You and your family ..
... will be in my prayers .
Reverend , don 't answer the door for anyone ..
... not after dark .
Not even for me .
Goodnight .
[ instrumental music ]
[ dramatic music ]
Mrs. Macklin ? There 's something out here . Please !
Quick ! Mrs. Macklin !
[ pounding on door ]
Mrs. Macklin , quick !
There 's somethin ' out here , please !
Move to the window so I can see you .
Alright .
Inside , quickly !
[ music continues ]
Oh , thank you . Thank you .
What is that thing ?
I don 't know .
It 's been here for as long as we have .
Why did you stay ?
My husband doesn 't believe me .
He - - he hasn 't seen it ?
But sure he .. When Emma saw it ..
[ dramatic music ]
Oh , no .
I 've said too much .
Pity .
I was havin ' such a good time !
[ intense music ]
[ growling ]
[ howling ]
[ Lizzy breathing heavily ]
[ panting ]
[ instrumental music ]
[ music continues ]
[ breathing heavily ]
[ inhales ]
[ horse neighing ]
[ exhales ]
Oh , hey , Lizzy !
Lizzy ?
It 's me .
[ dramatic music ]
Hey .
Look at me . It 's alright .
It 's alright .
Okay . It 's alright .
Hey .
What happened ? You hurt ?
I saw the reverend on the way home .
He said you were very hospitable .
No .
[ sobs ]
Hey .
Lizzy ?
[ instrumental music ]
[ music continues ]
[ indistinct chatter ]
You should have woke me .
That is probably the longest sleep you 've had in a while .
[ birds chirping ]
All the men are gone , but , uh ..
... I brought you something .
[ dramatic music ]
Good Lord , Lizzy , you 've gone pale .
I just wasn 't expecting to see anything of theirs again .
They 're just books .
Besides ..
... they 'll help us pass the winter .
Occupy our minds .
Occupy my mind ?
Let 's get it inside .
[ instrumental music ]
[ grunting ]
[ rain pattering ]
" I demand a creature of another sex
" but as hideous as myself .
" It is true we shall be monsters
" cut off from all the world .
" But on that account
" we shall be more attached to one another .
" Our lives will not be happy ..
" ... but they will be harmless
" and free from the misery I now feel .
" Oh , my creator , make me happy .
" Let me feel gratitude towards you for one benefit .
" Let me see that I excite the sympathy
of some existing thing .. "
[ intense music ]
[ instrumental music ]
[ music continues ]
[ door opens ]
Oh , it 's getting cold .
Maybe you should pull out the extra blankets .
I burned this .
- It was Emma 's . - She was reading this ?
She was seeing something .
Lizzy ..
- There is something out there . - Enough .
Just enough . Enough .
I really thought we were past this .
Nothing , nothing good can come
from reading this nonsense .
Look what happened to Emma , she took
her own life , for Christ 's sake !
I 'm not so sure she did .
No , Lizzy .
You really shouldn 't be out after dark .
Y - - you don 't know what 's out there .
There is nothing out there !
Oh , God . Isaac , please !
Where 's your gun , Lizzy ?
[ eerie music ]
[ explosion ]
[ clattering ]
[ groans ]
[ screams ]
[ music continues ]
[ indistinct whispering ]
[ screams ]
[ clatters ]
[ groans ]
[ screams ]
[ breathing heavily ]
[ music continues ]
[ indistinct whispering ]
[ Emma humming ]
[ humming continues ]
Isaac .
How long have you had this ?
It 's not safe here .
Isaac .
Isaac , we have to leave .
We have to get out .
How did she get your gun , Lizzy ?
It doesn 't matter .
- Emma ? - Lizzy !
[ laughing ]
Isaac , I don 't care what happened .
[ instrumental music ]
- We need to go home . - I told Gideon .
I told Gideon that he should leave
and that he shouldn 't come back .
What did you do ?
Isaac ... please untie me .
You don 't understand what 's happening ..
... but I do , I 've seen it .
[ Emma laughing ]
Isaac ! Please untie me !
- She was pregnant . - Oh , God , no .
It 's just gonna be me , you , Isaac ..
[ thunder rumbling ]
- You killed her . - No . It wasn 't me .
It was .
[ dramatic music ]
[ growling ]
Isaac .
There 's something here .
[ laughing ]
Lizzy !
[ music continues ]
It 's right there .
There is nothing !
Lizzy .
[ gunshot ]
No .
[ grunts ]
[ instrumental music ]
[ breathing heavily ]
[ music continues ]
Good morning .
Morning , reverend .
How was your journey ?
Fine . Thank you .
I have something for you .
I came prepared .
You can never be too prepared .
The Lord 's blessing be with you .
And with you .
[ music continues ]
[ instrumental music ]
There 's something out there .
There is nothing out there .
This land , there 's something wrong with it .
Your mind is looking for things to worry about .
First baby and all .
[ music continues ]
It 's just you and me .
[ wind whooshing ]
[ instrumental music ]
[ music continues ]
[ dramatic music ]
[ instrumental music ]
[ music continues ]